<faq>
  <entry>
    <question>What academic support or tutoring services are available?</question>
    <answer>We have both one-on-one tutoring services available to students as well as LEAD sessions offered for many courses. A LEAD session is a session where once a week, students can go meet in a classroom with an upperclass mentor (who previously received an A in the course) to work through problems with homework, have study sessions, etc. During these sessions, the faculty member who teaches the class is also present if there were a problem that couldn’t be solved.</answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Are there opportunities to do undergraduate research?</question>
    <answer>Most of our students will participate in undergraduate research through the OURE program (Opportunities for Undergraduate Research). In this program, students will work on a year-long research project that is grant-funded by the university. In addition to the OURE program, many of our students assist faculty members with their research and receive stipends for their effors.</answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>How long does it typically take to complete the degree I’m interested in?</question>
    <answer>Our campus average for completing a degree is 4 ½ years. This varies as many of our engineering students will take slightly longer to graduate due to the extensive coursework. Many of them also go on co-op (where they are working directly for a company) and therefore take a semester off of classes.</answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Can I meet with a faculty member or student while I’m visiting?</question>
    <answer>Absolutely! When you come for either one of our visit events for prospective students or your own individual campus visit, you will have the opportunity to meet with a member of the academic department(s) of your choice.</answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>What if I change my mind about what I want to study?</question>
    <answer>Depending on what you are switching between, this is usually a very easy transition. As 90% of our students are in engineering, science, math or technology, there is a good amount of overlap between the courses they are taking and therefore making a transition between majors is easy. For students in Engineering, we also have the Freshman Engineering program where during their first year, students are taking courses in Calculus, Physics, Chemistry, etc. that all engineering majors need. They also take a course called Careers In Engineering that exposes them to all 15 of our engineering disciplines. This gives the student almost a year and a half before they have to be completely decided about what type of engineering they would like to choose.</answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>How does the school prepare graduates for professional positions?</question>
    <answer>Our students apply the theories they learn into the classroom on a regular basis through the use of our many labs. Many of the principles they apply in the real world are used through these labs so when they start their careers they are completely prepared for their jobs. They are also prepared for both industry and graduate school through the many opportunities for undergraduate research and internships/co-ops. Due to all of these resources being in place, our students have about an 85% placement rate at the time of graduation into jobs or graduate school.</answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Are students allowed to take courses outside their major program?</question>
    <answer>Definitely! We have many additional minors and programs on campus that students are allowed to take in order to satisfy their diverse interests.</answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>What kind of cultural events, clubs, and organizations are available? </question>
    <answer>Missouri S and T has over 200 different student organizations on campus and a variety of campus-wide activities and events for every student to engage in.   Our cultural events include our St. Patrick’s Day festivities, Celebrations of Nations, International Day of Peace, and monthly cultural programs.  For more information on these events and programs visit the websites below.
Clubs and Organizations: studentlife.mst.edu.
Cultural Events and Programs: lcprograms.mst.edu.</answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Is there a variety of shopping nearby? </question>
    <answer>Rolla, Mo offers a few shopping options to meet the various needs of its community.  There are a small variety of departments stores, such as JC Penny and K-mart, grocery stores as Wal-Mart and Kroger, drug stores such as Sinks Pharmacy and Walgreen, and a host of other specialty shops and other shopping options.  Not to mention the Osage Beach outlet mall, St. Louis, Columbia, and Springfield shopping options being a drive away. .</answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>What do students do for fun in the area? What kind of recreational opportunities are available nearby? </question>
    <answer>Rolla, MO is in the heart of some of Missouri’s most beautiful land.  Inside of the city, there’s bowling, skating, mini golf, the movie theatre, and the like.  Surrounding the city, there’re the Ozarks, Meramec Valley, and a variety of other places for activities such as hiking, cave exploring, zip-lining, go on float trips, skydiving, and camping.  Rolla, Mo is also in the middle of Columbia, Springfield, and St. Louis, which many students travel to for fun.
For more information on Rolla shopping and recreation: www.rollanet.org.</answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Does the school support students that are seeking co-ops and internships? </question>
    <answer>Missouri S and T has many opportunities to engage in co-ops and internships through our Career Opportunities and Employer Relations department (COER).  Students may attend the career fair or employer visits or check the MinerJobs board for opportunities.  These opportunities are paid and provide great on-the-job skills with organizations across the globe. </answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Is there a career center on campus and what services does it offer? </question>
    <answer>Career Opportunities and Employer Relations (COER) is our on-campus career center.  Ranked 17th in the nation among career centers for its excellence service to students, COER offers a multitude of resources for its students and alumni.  COER host resume writing workshops, mock interviews, etiquette dinners, and job search opportunities and resources.  We even have a suit closet from which our young men and women may get and keep their suits for occasions like career fairs and interviews.
For more information on career services visit: career.mst.edu.</answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>What are my living options? </question>
    <answer>Missouri S and T has 3 residential halls and an off campus apartment for its students.  For students within the appropriate interest, there is also Greek housing and Campus Christian housing.  Incoming freshman, students are required to live on campus for their first 2 years and are able to take advantage of all of these options with the exception of the off campus housing.  There is also a variety of affordable off-campus housing options available within the city of Rolla and its surrounding areas. .</answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>May I choose my own roommate? </question>
    <answer>For on-campus housing, students may either request a specific roommate when filling out their residential life questionnaire or be assigned a roommate.  These requests are honored whenever possible, but are not guaranteed.
For more information on on-campus housing: reslife.mst.edu.</answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Will I need a computer of my own or are they easily available on campus? </question>
    <answer>Many students bring their own computers from home. However we have plenty of computers available all over campus and are all linked to the network, making it easy to access you files on other computers. .</answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>How do I get athletic and event tickets? </question>
    <answer>You can purchase tickets to the games individually at the gate or you can purchase season tickets online at sports.mst.edu. The ticket price varies depending on the sport. Students currently enrolled at Missouri University of Science and Technology can receive free admission into athletic games free with a valid ID.
Learn more about game times at http://sports.mst.edu.</answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Can I bring a car, will I need it, and if so how do I get a parking permit? </question>
    <answer>You can bring a car on campus. Parking permits are available to incoming students on a first come, first serve basis. The total cost of a parking permit is $125 for an academic year.
Read more about parking at http://police.mst.edu.</answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>What services are offered for students with learning or physical disabilities? </question>
    <answer>Yes. Please check out http://dss.mst.edu.</answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>What transportation is available in the area? </question>
    <answer>There is a local taxi service. However, many things are in walking distance of campus. .</answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Are counseling services available? </question>
    <answer>Yes. Please check out http://counsel.mst.edu.</answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Is there an on-campus health center and what services does it offer? </question>
    <answer>The health center is located at 910 W. 10th St. Check out the services offered at http://studenthealth.mst.edu.</answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>After being admitted, what orientation programs does the school sponsor? </question>
    <answer>You can read more about the campus orientation programs offered at http://pro.mst.edu.</answer>
  </entry>
</faq>


 