<faq>
  <entry>
    <question>What academic support or tutoring services are available?</question>
    <answer>We have both one-on-one tutoring services available to students as well as LEAD sessions offered for many courses. A LEAD session is a session where once a week, students can go meet in a classroom with an upperclass mentor (who previously received an A in the course) to work through problems with homework, have study sessions, etc. During these sessions, the faculty member who teaches the class is also present if there were a problem that couldn’t be solved.</answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Are there opportunities to do undergraduate research?</question>
    <answer>Most of our students will participate in undergraduate research through the OURE program (Opportunities for Undergraduate Research). In this program, students will work on a year-long research project that is grant-funded by the university. In addition to the OURE program, many of our students assist faculty members with their research and receive stipends for their effors.</answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>How long does it typically take to complete the degree I’m interested in?</question>
    <answer>Our campus average for completing a degree is 4 ½ years. This varies as many of our engineering students will take slightly longer to graduate due to the extensive coursework. Many of them also go on co-op (where they are working directly for a company) and therefore take a semester off of classes.</answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Can I meet with a faculty member or student while I’m visiting?</question>
    <answer>Absolutely! When you come for either one of our visit events for prospective students or your own individual campus visit, you will have the opportunity to meet with a member of the academic department(s) of your choice.</answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>What if I change my mind about what I want to study?</question>
    <answer>Depending on what you are switching between, this is usually a very easy transition. As 90% of our students are in engineering, science, math or technology, there is a good amount of overlap between the courses they are taking and therefore making a transition between majors is easy. For students in Engineering, we also have the Freshman Engineering program where during their first year, students are taking courses in Calculus, Physics, Chemistry, etc. that all engineering majors need. They also take a course called Careers In Engineering that exposes them to all 15 of our engineering disciplines. This gives the student almost a year and a half before they have to be completely decided about what type of engineering they would like to choose.</answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>How does the school prepare graduates for professional positions?</question>
    <answer>Our students apply the theories they learn into the classroom on a regular basis through the use of our many labs. Many of the principles they apply in the real world are used through these labs so when they start their careers they are completely prepared for their jobs. They are also prepared for both industry and graduate school through the many opportunities for undergraduate research and internships/co-ops. Due to all of these resources being in place, our students have about an 85% placement rate at the time of graduation into jobs or graduate school.</answer>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Are students allowed to take courses outside their major program?</question>
    <answer>Definitely! We have many additional minors and programs on campus that students are allowed to take in order to satisfy their diverse interests.</answer>
  </entry>
</faq>
 